Guide to the Peter S. Craig Papers, 1904-1983 MS2066
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Peter S. Craig papers
1904-1983
1960-1975
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Craig, Peter Stebbins
MS2066
50 Linear Feet
Peter Stebbins Craig was a lawyer in Washington, D.C. who led legal challenges against the construction of interstate highways through the city in the 1960s and 1970s. Taking the side of residents whose homes would be razed for new freeways, Craig successfully battled developers, business leaders, and members of Congress to block seven multilane highways that would have destroyed 200,000 housing units within the city. This collection contains reports and studies, correspondence, legal documents, clippings, reference materials, and index cards documenting Craig's work in transportation planning in Washington, DC.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Peter S. Craig, 1986.
Historical or Biographical Note
Peter Stebbins Craig was a lawyer in Washington, D.C. who led legal challenges against the construction of interstate highways through the city in the 1960s and 1970s. Taking the side of residents whose homes would be razed for new freeways, Craig successfully battled developers, business leaders, and members of Congress to block seven multilane highways that would have destroyed 200,000 housing units within the city.
Born in Brooklyn, NY, in 1928, Peter Stebbins Craig spent his childhood in Oberlin, OH and attended Oberlin College and Yale Law School, from which he graduated in 1953 as a member of the law review. He first joined the law firm of Covington and Burling, and later became counsel at Southern Railway in 1960, working there until he retired in 1989 with one break from 1967-69 to serve at the U.S. Department of Transportation.
Craig first opposed freeway construction in the city when he became aware of plans to build a major new artery through his Cleveland Park neighborhood, from Georgetown to Bethesda, in the late 1950s. In 1960, as part of the citizen organization Northwest Committee for Transportation Planning, Craig and two other lawyers won a 5-year ban on freeways west of Rock Creek and north of M street, stalling the proposed highway. But success was short-lived. In response to the ban, developers shifted their proposed highway to the west, proposing a North Central Freeway that would have sliced through the city from Capitol Hill to Silver Spring, destroying 4000 homes in a primarily African American neighborhood.
Joining with the community planning organization Committee of 100 on the Federal City, Craig then pushed back against all planned freeways, arguing that they violated a law from the 1880s allowing no road in the city wider than Pennsylvania Avenue. He and his team won in the U.S. Court of Appeals in 1968, though they still faced significant opposition in Congress, which controlled the District's spending and attempted to push the projects through by withholding money for Washington's planned subway system until the highways were built. This impasse lasted until 1976, when the Department of Transportation intervened on the side of the District, freeing the money for the subway without requiring construction of the highways.
Many of the proposed highway projects, including the proposed Three Sisters Bridge over the Potomac, faced significant public protest, including violence and arrests at a 1969 City Council meeting. Craig and fellow volunteer lawyers won a victory in U.S. District Court in 1970, ordering work on the Three Sisters Bridge to stop.
Transportation projects that were canceled in part due to Craig's work include: the Three Sisters Bridge across the Potomac, connecting to I-66; Interstate 266; the North Central Freeway (from Capitol Hill to Silver Spring); the South Leg Freeway; and Interstate 70-S/Northwest Freeway (along Wisconsin Avenue to Bethesda). Craig was named a Washingtonian of the Year by Washingtonian Magazine in 1972. Reflecting on his struggle against the freeways 30 years later in 2000, Craig told the Washington Post, "While I've done a lot of things in my life, this has made the most difference."
Craig was also an avid genealogist. As a Fellow of the American Society of Genealogists and a Fellow of the Genealogical Society of Pennsylvania, he wrote prolifically on the Swedish Colonial Period in the Delaware Valley. He died on November 26, 2009.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains reports and studies, correspondence, legal documents, clippings, and index cards documenting the work of lawyer Peter S. Craig in opposition to the construction of freeways through Washington, D.C. The bulk of the material dates from 1960 to 1975, when Craig was active in this work, though some of Craig's reference materials—such as studies and clippings—date as far back as 1904. As a member of the Committee of 100 on the Federal City and the Northwest Committee for Transportation Planning, Craig drafted legal challenges to proposed highway construction on behalf of neighborhood groups whose homes were in the highways' paths. He ultimately helped derail plans for seven multilane highways through the District, including highways that would have tunneled under the Mall, tunneled under K Street, and destroyed 200,000 housing units within the city.
The material remains, physically, primarily in the order in which it arrived, much of it in Craig's own three-ring binders. The titles of the folders and binders have been arranged into series and alphabetized in a finding aid to provide research access. Because some materials were consolidated during processing and the boxes were not subsequently renumbered, some box numbers no longer exist (box numbers 3, 5, 9, 27, 28, 31, 55, 60, 63, 68, and 71).
Reports, studies, and correspondence in this collection come from many local transportation agencies and organizations engaged in city planning as far back as the early 1900s, including: The Committee of 100 on the Federal City, the Northwest Committee for Transportation Planning, the National Capital Planning Commission, the Washington Metropolitan Area Transportation Authority, the American Civic Association, and many local citizens' associations. Legal cases include D.C. Federation of Civic Associations, Inc. v. Airis and D.C. Federation of Civic Associations v. Volpe, which were ultimately victories for Craig and his fellow lawyers over business and government interests attempting to build freeways through the District, as well as many other suits brought by citizens' associations.
Transportation projects that figure heavily in the collection—projects which were canceled in part due to Craig's work—include: the Three Sisters Bridge across the Potomac, connecting to I-66; Interstate 266; the North Central Freeway (from Capitol Hill to Silver Spring); the South Leg Freeway; and Interstate 70-S/Northwest Freeway (along Wisconsin Avenue to Bethesda).
This material was donated to Gelman Library by Peter S. Craig in 1986.
Collection Organization
Arranged in five series: 1. Reports and studies; 2. Correspondence and memos; 3. Legal cases; 4. Clippings; and 5. Index cards.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Related Materials
In The Metro Oral History collection is an interview with Peter Craig conducted by Dr. Zachary Schrag. The recording and transcript of that interview has been uploaded to Internet Archive. This link will take you to all the MS2214 interviews and transcripts. https://archive.org/search.php?query=ms2214%20george%20washington%20university&and[]=subject%3A%22MS2214%22
Historic preservation; Transportation; Planning; Urban transportation; Maps; Home rule; Washington (D.C.); Express highways; Zoning; City traffic; Subways; Committee of 100 on the Federal City (Washington, D.C.); Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority; United States. National Capital Planning Commission
- Reports and studies, 1904-1984; Series 1; 25 Linear Feet
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by title of report or study. Some smaller reports are gathered together into folders with titles like "Pamphlets and Articles" or "Reports and Studies."
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains reports, studies, pamphlets, articles, and data on transportation planning, traffic, zoning, and related legislation in Washington, DC. They date from 1904 to 1984, though the majority are from 1960 to 1975. They were gathered and used by Peter S. Craig as part of his legal work in opposition to freeway construction in the city.
  - 86th Congress (1959-60) Legislative Action on Route 70-S, 1960; Series 1 (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - 86th Congress Joint Committee on Washington Metropolitan Problems, 1958-1960; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - A.D. Little Report and Hartzog Agreement, National Capital Planning Commission minutes, 1966; Series 1 (Box 45, Binder 3)
  - American Motorist, 1960-1969; Series 1 (Box 33, Binder 3)
  - Bridges, 1962-1965; Series 1 (Box 52, Binder 1)
  - Commissioners' Evaluation of NCTA Plan 02/18/1963 draft, 1963 February 18; Series 1 (Box 40, Binder 7)
  - Committee of 100 on the Future Development of Washington, 1910-1916; Series 1 (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - Committee of 100, material for book, 1927-1931; Series 1 (Box 65, Folder 11)
  - Committee of 100 reports, 1924-1957; Series 1 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Community Renewal Program Report, 1966; Series 1 (Box 67, Volume 3)
  - Comprehensive Plan for the National Capital, 1975; Series 1 (Box 67, Volume 5)
  - DC Administrative Procedures Act, 1971-1972; Series 1 (Box 37, Binder 8)
  - DC Administrative Procedure Act legislative history, undated; Series 1 (Box 37, Binder 6)
  - DC Area Transit Compact, 1965-1966; series 1 (Box 25, Binder 6)
  - DC Committee for Balanced Transportation, undated; Series 1 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - DC Cordon Survey, 1968; Series 1 (Box 41, Volume 1)
  - DC Cordon Survey, 1969; Series 1 (Box 41, Volume 2)
  - DC Cordon Survey, 1970; Series 1 (Box 41, Volume 3)
  - DC Cordon Survey, Summary Report, 1970; Series 1 (Box 41, Volume 4)
  - DC Federation of Citizens Assocations, undated; Series 1 (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - DC Highway Case Notes, undated; Series 1 (Box 52, Binder 3)
  - DC Highway Finance, 1955-1974; Series 1 (Box 34, Binder 7)
  - DC highway statutes (since 1800), 1965; Series 1 (Box 29, Binder 4)
  - DC Population Data, undated; Series 1 (Box 62, Folder 15)
  - DC Public Works Plan -- Highways and Traffic, 1966; Series 1 (Box 56, Binder 1)
  - DC Transit System, Inc., undated; Series 1 (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - DC Transit Traffic Counts, 1955; Series 1 (Box 62, Folder 12)
  - DC Transit Traffic Counts, 1965; Series 1 (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, 1928; Series 1 (Box 47, Binder 7)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, 1929-1944; Series 1 (Box 47, Binder 8)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, 1945; Series 1 (Box 47, Binder 9)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, 1946-1952; Series 1 (Box 48, Binder 8)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, 1953-1955; Series 1 (Box 48, Binder 9)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, 1955-1956; Series 1 (Box 48, Binder 7)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, 1956-1958; Series 1 (Box 48, Binder 6)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, 1958-1959; Series 1 (Box 48, Binder 5)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, 1960; Series 1 (Box 48, Binder 4)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, 1960-1961; Series 1 (Box 48, Binder 3)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, 1961-1962; Series 1 (Box 48, Binder 2)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 1, 1962; Series 1 (Box 49, Binder 8)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 2, 1962; Series 1 (Box 49, Binder 7)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 1, 1963; Series 1 (Box 49, Binder 6)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 2, 1963; Series 1 (Box 49, Binder 5)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 1, 1964; Series 1 (Box 49, Binder 3)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 2, 1964; Series 1 (Box 49, Binder 4)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 1, 1965; Series 1 (Box 49, Binder 2)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 2, 1965; Series 1 (Box 49, Binder 1)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 3, 1965; Series 1 (Box 50, Binder 2)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 4, 1965; Series 1 (Box 51, Binder 1)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 5, 1965; Series 1 (Box 50, Binder 1)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 1, 1966; Series 1 (Box 50, Binder 3)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 2, 1966; Series 1 (Box 51, Binder 2)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 3, 1966; Series 1 (Box 51, Binder 3)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 4, 1966; Series 1 (Box 51, Binder 4)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 6, 1966; Series 1 (Box 51, Binder 5)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 7, 1966; Series 1 (Box 51, Binder 6)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 1, 1967; Series 1 (Box 51, Binder 7)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 2, 1967; Series 1 (Box 51, Binder 8)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 3, 1967; Series 1 (Box 19, Binder 4)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 4, 1967; Series 1 (Box 19, Binder 8)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 1, 1968; Series 1 (Box 19, Binder 9)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 2, 1968; Series 1 (Box 19, Binder 5)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 1, 1969; Series 1 (Box 19, Binder 7)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 2, 1969; Series 1 (Box 19, Binder 6)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, 1970; Series 1 (Box 20, Binder 4)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 2, 1970; Series 1 (Box 19, Binder 1)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 1, 1971; Series 1 (Box 19, Binder 3)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 2, 1971; Series 1 (Box 19, Binder 2)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, 1971-1972; Series 1 (Box 20, Binder 5)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 1, 1972; Series 1 (Box 20, Binder 6)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 2, 1972; Series 1 (Box 20, Binder 7)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 1, 1973; Series 1 (Box 20, Binder 8)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, Vol. 2, 1973; Series 1 (Box 20, Binder 9)
  - DC Transportation Planning Reports, 1974-1975; Series 1 (Box 13, Binder 1)
  - District of Columbia Interstate System [1], 1971; Series 1 (Box 70, Volume 2)
  - District of Columbia Interstate System [2], 1971; Series 1 (Box 70, Volume 3)
  - Easing the Effect on People of the Construction of the North Leg of the Inner Loop, 1963; Series 1 (Box 1, Binder 5)
  - Engineering Estimate on Northwest Freeway, Interstate I-70S, 1959; Series 1 (Box 32, Binder 2)
  - Engineering Plans and Cost Estimates, 1965; Series 1 (Box 1, Volume 5)
  - EPA parking regulations and court cases in DC Circuit Court, 1973; Series 1 (Box 34, Binder 6)
  - Federal aid highway legislation, 1965-1966; Series 1 (Box 40, Binder 3)
  - Federal Capital Improvements Program for the National Capital Region, 1979-1984; Series 1 (Box 72, Volume 1)
  - Federal City Luncheon, 1942; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Federal Employee Parking and Transportation Survey, Vol. 1, 1962; Series 1 (Box 1, Volume 1)
  - Final Report, Location of the Easy Leg, Interchange B, and the North Leg -- East Section, 1967; Series 1 (Box 66, Volume 2)
  - First District Element of the Comprehensive Plan, 1977; Series 1 (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - Friendship Heights, 1970-1972; Series 1 (Box 29, Binder 6)
  - George Washington Memorial Parkway, 1927-1930; Series 1 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Government reports, 1912-1928; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Government reports, 1958-1965; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Government reports, 1973-1976; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Handbook for Speakers -- Interstate Commission on the Potomac River Basin, 1951; Series 1 (Box 35, Volume 3)
  - Highway budget, FY1961-62, 1961-1962; Series 1 (Box 40, Binder 8)
  - Highway budget, FY1963, Series 1 (Box 45, Binder 10)
  - Highway budget, FY1964, Series 1 (Box 45, Binder 11)
  - Highway budget, FY1966, Series 1 (Box 45, Binder 9)
  - Highway Fund Finances, undated; Series 1 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Highway Inventory -- history, undated; Series 1 (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Highway legislation, 1964; series 1 (Box 24, Binder 1)
  - Highway lobby publications, undated; Series 1 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Highway Transportation in the Washington Metropolitan Area of Virginia, 1953; Series 1 (Box 1, Volume 6)
  - Home Rule Act, Comprehensive Plan and Zoning, 1973-1975; Series 1 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Housing, 1945-1959; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - H.R. 11487, undated; Series 1 (Box 47, Binder 3)
  - H.R. 16000 DC government's revised report, 1968; Series 1 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - I-66, 1973; Series 1 (Box 1, Binder 2)
  - I-66 Corridor Transportation Alternatives Study, 1973; Series 1 (Box 69, Volume 6)
  - I-66 Corridor Transportation Arteries Study, 1973; Series 1 (Box 69, Volume 1)
  - I-66 Department of Transportation review, 1974-1975; Series 1 (Box 34, Binder 8)
  - I-66 location reports, Arlington County, 1958; Series 1 (Box 26, Binder 1)
  - I-66 hearings, 1970 December; Series 1 (Box 47, Binder 4)
  - I-66 hearings, Arlington County, 1958; Series 1 (Box 26, Binder 2)
  - I-66 TPB review, 1973-1974; Series 1 (Box 34, Binder 9)
  - I-266 Design Hearing Information, undated; Series 1 (Box 67, Volume 2)
  - I-266 testimony and statements, 1959-1967; Series 1 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Improving Bus Service (Virginia-DC), H. Bain for National Capital Transportation Agency, undated; Series 1 (Box 45, Binder 4)
  - Interstate Highway History Project proposal, 1984; Series 1 (Box 62, Folder 18)
  - Joint Committee on the National Capital [1 of 2], 1943-1958; Series 1 (Box 65, Folder 12)
  - Joint Committee on the National Capital [2 of 2], 1943-1958; Series 1 (Box 65, Folder 13)
  - Joint Committee on Washington Metropolitan Problems, Index, 1958-1960; Series 1 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Land use research, 1958-1972; Series 1 (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Law, undated; Series 1 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Legislation, 1961-1962; Series 1 (Box 65, Binder 2)
  - Legislation, 1963-1964; series 1 (Box 25, Binder 1)
  - Legislation, 1973; Series 1 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Location Study for the East Leg and Interchange B of the Inner Loop Freeway and North Leg -- East Section, 1965; Series 1 (Box 66, Volume 3)
  - Location Studies, Interstate 266, 1964; Series 1 (Box 66, Volume 8)
  - Maps and plans, oversize [including Patowmack Canal, Great Falls, VA; National Memorial Stadium; and Roosevelt Memorial], undated; Series 1 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Maryland National Capital Park and Planning Commission "On Wedges and Corridors", undated; Series 1 (Box 48, Binder 1)
  - Mass Transportation Survey, National Capital Region, 1958; Series 1 (Box 66, Volume 7)
  - Mass Transportation Survey, National Capital Region, 1958; Series 1 (Box 66, Volume 8)
  - Mass Transportation Survey, National Capital Region, 1959; Series 1 (Box 69, Volume 5)
  - Modal Split Studies, undated; Series 1 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - National Capital Planning Commission (NCPC) Transportation Committee, 1966; Series 1 (Box 40, Binder 4)
  - National Capital Planning Commission transcript, May 5, 1966, 1966 May 05; Series 1 (Box 45, Binder 6)
  - National Capital Planning Commission transcript, September 15, 1966, 1966 September 15; Series 1 (Box 45, Binder 8)
  - National Capital Planning Commission transcript, October 13, 1966, 1966 October 13; Series 1 (Box 45, Binder 7)
  - National Capital Planning Commission (NCPC) transcript June 9, 1966, 1966 June 09; Series 1 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - National Capital Transportation Act of 1960 legislative history, 1960-1961; series 1 (Box 25, Binder 2)
  - National Capital Transportation Act of 1965, series 1 (Box 25, Binder 4)
  - National Capital Transportation Agency, 1961-1967; Series 1 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - National Capital Transportation Agency study of Bus Rapid Transit Operations, 1963; Series 1 (Box 35, Volume 1)
  - National Capital Transportation Agency Appendix to November 1, 1962 Report to the President, Volume II: Use of Railroad Facilities, 1963; Series 1 (Box 15, Volume 2)
  - National Capital Transportation Agency Appendix to November 1, 1962 Report to the President, Volume II: Use of Railroad Facilities, Series 1 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - National Capital Transportation Agency Appendix to November 1, 1962 Report to the President, Volume IV: A Model for Estimating Travel Mode Usage, Series 1 (Box 1, Volume 3)
  - National Capital Transportation Agency Appendix to November 1, 1962 Report to the President, Engineering, 1963; Series 1 (Box 15, Volume 1)
  - National Capital Transportation Agency Appendix to the November 1, 1962 Report to the President, Volume VI: Organization and Finance, Series 1 (Box 35, Volume 2)
  - North-Central Freeway Engineering Feasibility Report, 1964; Series 1 (Box 70, Volume 4)
  - Northern Virginia Land Use and Usefulness, undated; Series 1 (Box 69, Volume 3)
  - Northwest Committee -- Mrs. Luchs, land use research, 1936-1960; Series 1 (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Pamphlets and articles, 1904-1918; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Pamphlets and articles, 1919-1927; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Pamphlets and articles, 1928-1937; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Pamphlets and articles, 1944-1952; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Pamphlets and articles, 1960-1968; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - A Parking Program for Washington, 1947; Series 1 (Box 66, Volume 6)
  - Parking Tax, 1972; Series 1 (Box 29, Binder 3)
  - Parks, 1929-1935; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Pollution, 1968-1973; Series 1 (Box 1, Binder 4)
  - Postwar Highway Plan, 1946-1947; Series 1 (Box 1, Binder 1)
  - Potomac River, undated; Series 1 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Potomac River Basin reports [1 of 10], undated; Series 1 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Potomac River Basin reports [2 of 10], undated; Series 1 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Potomac River Basin reports [3 of 10], undated; Series 1 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Potomac River Basin reports [4 of 10], undated; Series 1 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Potomac River Basin reports [5 of 10], undated; Series 1 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Potomac River Basin reports [6 of 10], undated; Series 1 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Potomac River Basin reports [7 of 10], undated; Series 1 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Potomac River Basin reports [8 of 10], undated; Series 1 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Potomac River Basin reports [9 of 10], undated; Series 1 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Potomac River Basin reports [10 of 10], undated; Series 1 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Potomac Valley, undated; Series 1 (Box 69, Volume 2)
  - Potomac Valley Conservation and Recreation Council, undated; Series 1 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Preliminary Six-Year Plan for Post-War Washington, 1946; Series 1 (Box 32, Binder 1)
  - The Probem of the Urban Intersection, 1946; Series 1 (Box 66, Volume 4)
  - Program for Comprehensive Planning and Development in National Capital Region, Wise, 1965; Series 1 (Box 45, Binder 5)
  - Proposed I-66 Corridor Transportation Improvements -- Final Environmental Impact / Section 4(f) Statement, 1974; Series 1 (Box 13, Binder 3)
  - Proposed Three Sisters Bridge -- Statement and Exhibits of Committee of 100 on the Federal City, 1961; Series 1 (Box 33, Binder 4)
  - Report on Downtown Progress, 1960-1961; Series 1 (Box 65, Folder 14)
  - Report of the Location of the Northeast Freeway, 1960; Series 1 (Box 66, Volume 1)
  - Reports and studies, 1907-1933; Series 1 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Reports and studies, 1940-1958; Series 1 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Reports and studies, 1930-1961; Series 1 (Box 22)
  - Reports and studies, 1930-1977; Series 1 (Box 30)
  - Reports and studies, 1960-1963; Series 1 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Reports and studies, 1961-1966; Series 1 (Box 2)